<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://daniel.feldroy.com/</id>
    <title>Daniel Roy Greenfeld</title>
    <updated>2022-11-03T21:39:17.543Z</updated>
    <generator>Next.js using Feed for Node.js</generator>
    <author>
        <name>Daniel Roy Greenfeld</name>
        <email>daniel@feldroy.com</email>
        <uri>https://daniel.feldroy.com</uri>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://daniel.feldroy.com"/>
    <subtitle>Inside the head of Daniel Roy Greenfeld</subtitle>
    <logo>https://daniel.feldroy.com/images/pydanny-cartwheel.png</logo>
    <icon>https://daniel.feldroy.com/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2022, Daniel Roy Greenfeld</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting s3 pre-signed URLS using the Node.js AWS SDK v3]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.feldroy.com/posts/2022-06-18-s3-getsigned-url-nodejs-aws-sdk-3</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.feldroy.com/posts/2022-06-18-s3-getsigned-url-nodejs-aws-sdk-3"/>
        <updated>2022-06-18T22:20:50.520Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An easy-to-find copy/pastable reference for creating pre-signed URLs for getting of files using the Node.js AWS SDK v3.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An easy-to-find copy/pastable reference for creating pre-signed URLs for getting of files using the Node.js AWS SDK v3.</p>
<h1>Background</h1>
<p>Maybe there's a reference in the docs that provides an easy-to-use documentation of the AWS SDK v3 method for creating pre-signed URLs using Node (or TypeScript). Alas, after 45 minutes of googling, stack overflowing, and other searching I couldn't find it. Yes, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/developer/generate-presigned-url-modular-aws-sdk-javascript">the docs had examples</a>, but they weren't copy/pastable for lazy/productive coders like myself. Perhaps I need to improve my search skills? I managed to solve it, but that took more effort than I expected.</p>
<p>For what it is worth, I hope the maintainers of the Node.js AWS SDK v3 add a copy/pastable version somewhere more obvious. The official docs will show up in searches before this article.</p>
<p>In any case, I finally dug in and figured it out. So I can find it again in the future, I'm posting it here.</p>
<h1>Install Dependencies</h1>
<pre><code class="language-bash">yarn add @aws-sdk/s3-request-presigner
yarn add @aws-sdk/client-s3
</code></pre>
<h1>Create Utility Function</h1>
<p>I encapsulated my solution in a function in <code>s3FileFetch.js</code> so I could use it accros a project:</p>
<pre><code class="language-javascript">import { getSignedUrl } from "@aws-sdk/s3-request-presigner";
import { S3Client, GetObjectCommand } from "@aws-sdk/client-s3";

// Create the config obj with credentials
// Always use environment variables or config files
// Don't hardcode your keys into code
const config = {
  credentials: {
    accessKeyId: process.env.AWS_ACCESS_KEY_ID,
    secretAccessKey: process.env.AWS_SECRET_ACCESS_KEY,
  },
  region: "us-west-2",
};
// Instantiate a new s3 client
const client = new S3Client(config);

async function getSignedFileUrl(fileName, bucket, expiresIn) {
  // Instantiate the GetObject command,
  // a.k.a. specific the bucket and key
  const command = new GetObjectCommand({
    Bucket: bucket,
    Key: fileName,
  });

  // await the signed URL and return it
  return await getSignedUrl(client, command, { expiresIn });
}

export default getSignedFileUrl;
</code></pre>
<h1>Usage</h1>
<pre><code class="language-javascript">import getFileUrl from "/lib/s3FileFetch";

async function returnThumbnail(thumbnail_key) {
  return await getFileUrl(thumbnail_key, "my_bucket", 3600);
}
</code></pre>
<h1>Any Suggestions?</h1>
<p>This works but I'm certain it can be improved. If you have any suggestions on how to do this action better, let me know in social media or email!</p>
<h1>Updates</h1>
<ul>
<li>2022-06-19: Moved configuration and instantiation of <code>s3</code> object out of the function thanks to a suggestion by <a href="https://github.com/defy93">Jake Patrick</a>.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Roy Greenfeld</name>
            <email>daniel@feldroy.com</email>
            <uri>https://daniel.feldroy.com</uri>
        </author>
        <contributor>
            <name>Daniel Roy Greenfeld</name>
            <email>daniel@feldroy.com</email>
            <uri>https://daniel.feldroy.com</uri>
        </contributor>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Farewell to Aaron & Company]]></title>
        <id>https://daniel.feldroy.com/posts/2022-05-07-farewell-aaron-and-company</id>
        <link href="https://daniel.feldroy.com/posts/2022-05-07-farewell-aaron-and-company"/>
        <updated>2022-05-07T22:20:50.520Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aaron & Company was a plumbing supplies firm started by my great-grandfather over 100 years ago and incorporated in 1932. And now it is being sold.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aaron &#x26; Company was a plumbing supplies firm started by my great-grandfather about 100 years ago and incorporated in 1932. And now it is being sold. Unlike the rest of my family I have almost no memories of the business, but being able to talk about it was always a point of pride. Today, with it existing for just a few days more, I wish I had spent more time there as a teenager and adult.</p>
<p>The firm was more than just a business. My great-grandfather started the company, but his son progressively took care of their workers. For decades they all got good pay, full benefits, and everyone's opinion was respected. These are good values many companies refuse to even consider, or if they want to match them, struggle to do so. Yet Aaron and Company has done it for decades.</p>
<p>They also were selling solar equipment in the late 1970s, if not sooner. Considering my <a href="/posts/whats-the-best-thing-about-working-for-octopus-energy-part-1">career mission of addressing climate change</a>, I find that really awesome.</p>
<p>Note: As more stories and photos emerge I'll be expanding this article.</p>
<h1>The Notification</h1>
<p>From an uncle who was the last Aaron family partner in the firm:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Effective May 23, 2022, Aaron &#x26; Company will cease to exist as Aaron &#x26; Company after roughly 100 years, a few weeks shy of twenty years since my retirement.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>It will be sold to Ferguson Supply.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1>History of Aaron and Company</h1>
<p>This was the official history of the company:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Now one of the region's largest plumbing-heating-cooling wholesalers, Aaron &#x26; Company began nearly a century ago in New Brunswick, NJ. Founded by immigrant plumber Isadore Aaron in the early 1900's, and incorporated in 1932, the business began serving local plumbers out of Aaron's basement.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Isadore's son, Maurice, took over the supply house, then located at a New Brunswick storefront, and moved it to a larger downtown location in 1950. Maurice Aaron began to expand the company westward, opening branches in Flemington (1961) and Somerville (1970). Headquarters moved to New Brunswick's industrial zone in 1979, where new partners Frank Laudino, Jeffrey Aaron and Gerald Portnoy opened the first Aaron Bath Centers showroom. A second showroom was added later to the Flemington facility.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Under the next generation leadership of Barry Portnoy, Jeffrey Aaron, Frank Laudino Jr., and Richard Laudino, Aaron &#x26; Company added a branch in Trenton (1994) and a full showroom branch in Freehold (1996). We opened a new 120,000+ square-foot computerized central distribution center in Piscataway in 1998, where our corporate headquarters is now located. Four years later, Jeffrey Aaron retired. In 2006 we renovated our New Brunswick facility and created a brand new facet to our business, Kitchens. We now offer design services, and an outstanding selection of kitchen cabinetry and accessories. In addition, the plumbing showroom in New Brunswick was renovated and all of the showrooms have been renamed to become: The "Aaron Kitchen and Bath Design Gallery".</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>In 2010 Aaron &#x26; Company acquired S.Franklin and Son in Fairfield, NJ; the 11 Gloria Lane location is Aaron &#x26; Company’s most northern location to date. With the S. Franklin acquisition Aaron &#x26; Company becomes a commercial HVAC supplier with Sheet metal, Greenheck fans and Reznor.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>In 2013, shortly after Hurricane Sandy, Aaron &#x26; Company acquires Dickson Plumbing Supply in Brielle, New Jersey. After almost a year of working in a temporary “pop-up” branch due to the extensive damage done to the building due to Hurricane Sandy, Aaron &#x26; Company officially opens 1 Union Ave, Brielle NJ in May of 2014.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Today, Aaron and Company employs over 150 people at it's eight locations including the four that house the Aaron Kitchen and Bath Design Gallery showrooms. We are now considered one of the largest independent wholesale distributors of plumbing, heating, and cooling products in New Jersey.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1>Photos</h1>
<p><em>If anyone has photos or other media related to Aaron &#x26; Company, share and I'll add them below.</em></p>
<p><img src="/aaronco/logo.png" alt=""></p>
<p><em>The logo was designed by my grandmother. It was the official company logo. It was on all signs and trucks at all the locations. It was a source of pride for my mother and I that her effort was used for decades.</em></p>
<p><img src="/aaronco/History1.png" alt=""></p>
<p><em>This photo of the company catalog taken in autumn of 1958 features either my great-grandfather or grandfather. Waiting for an answer on who it actually might be.</em></p>
<p><img src="/aaronco/History2.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p><em>This photo was probably taken in 1979, during the move from downtown New Bruinswick to Piscataway. The sign mentions "solar", meaning my family has been into renewable energy for decades.</em></p>
<p><img src="/aaronco/aeriel-new-bruinswick-with-arrow.png" alt=""></p>
<p><em>The HQ marked by the arrow opened in 1950 and closed when Johnson &#x26; Johnson bought the site for its headquarters in the late 1970s. I have faint memories of visiting there as a child.</em></p>
<p><img src="/aaronco/aeriel-new-bruinswick-no-arrow.png" alt=""></p>
<p><em>Another aeriel shot, but no arrow. What's striking is the massive town gas container in the upper left of the neighborhood, something that was common in the older era for cities all over the world.</em></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Roy Greenfeld</name>
            <email>daniel@feldroy.com</email>
            <uri>https://daniel.feldroy.com</uri>
        </author>
        <contributor>
            <name>Daniel Roy Greenfeld</name>
            <email>daniel@feldroy.com</email>
            <uri>https://daniel.feldroy.com</uri>
        </contributor>
    </entry>
</feed>